<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="recent.xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
      xml:base="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/">

<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent</id>
<updated>2009-03-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>Waterken News</title>
<subtitle>Capability-based security on the Web</subtitle>
<link href="recent.html"/>
<link rel="self" href="recent.xml"/>
<logo>site/icon.gif</logo>
<icon>site/icon.gif</icon>
<author>
    <name>Tyler Close</name>
    <uri>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent.html</uri>
</author>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#9</id>
<updated>2009-03-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>Deferred vs promise</title>
<link href="http://groups.google.com/group/serverjs/browse_thread/thread/e93f73ef97e88439"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/serverjs">serverjs</a> group is
working on a set of APIs for server-side Javascript programming. I've joined in
on a <a
href="http://groups.google.com/group/serverjs/browse_thread/thread/e93f73ef97e88439">thread
about an API for asynchronous operations</a>. So far, the discussion has
centered around the differences between the <a
href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twisted_(software)#Deferreds">Deferred
concept from Twisted</a> and the <a
href="http://www.erights.org/elib/concurrency/refmech.html">promise concept</a>
from <a href="http://erights.org/">E</a> and <a
href="http://portal.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=54016">Barbara Liskov's work</a>.
Though I believe the Deferred concept is a direct descendant of the E promise,
the API is significantly different and doesn't support the most useful
programming idioms for asynchronous messaging. A Deferred doesn't support any
operations that can't just as easily be done with Promises. I'm hoping to
convince the serverjs group to adopt Promises instead of Deferreds;
specifically, the <a href="bang/">Javascript ref_send library</a>.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#8</id>
<updated>2009-01-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>ACLs don't</title>
<link href="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/aclsdont/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The ACL model is unable to make correct access decisions for interactions
involving more than two principals, since required information is not retained
across message sends. Though this deficiency has long been documented in the
published literature, it is not widely understood. This logic error in the ACL
model is exploited by both the clickjacking and Cross-Site Request Forgery
attacks that affect many Web applications.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#7</id>
<updated>2008-10-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>clickjacking: The Confused Deputy rides again!</title>
<link href="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/clickjacking/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The <a href="http://ha.ckers.org/blog/20080915/clickjacking/">announcement
of the clickjacking research</a> ignited interest in a number of Web exploits,
some of which seem new and others similar to known exploits. Already, there's
lots of
<a href="http://blog.whatwg.org/this-week-in-html-5-episode-7">discussion of
possible workarounds</a>, mainly focused on changes to the application's user
interface, or the browser's rendering logic. While the flexibility of the
browser's user interface languages gives clickjacking a polished look, this
flexibility isn't actually what enables these attacks. That blame lies with the
ambient authority model used by most web applications. If applications instead
used an explicit authorization model, they would not be vulnerable to
clickjacking and there would be no need to reduce the flexibility of the
browser's user interface languages. Web applications can be implemented to an
explicit authorization model without any change to Web protocols or
formats.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#6</id>
<updated>2008-09-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>Petname Tool: updated for Firefox 3</title>
<link href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/957"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>I've ported the Petname Tool to the new
Places API for bookmarks in Firefox 3.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#5</id>
<updated>2008-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>Can the evolution of programming languages inform usable security?</title>
<link href="http://usablesecurity.com/2008/07/24/testing-for-usable-security-what-relationship-if-any-does-it-have-to-product-design/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Richard Conlan blogs about a SOUPS 2008 panel that I participated in.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#4</id>
<updated>2008-04-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>Using promises to orchestrate Web interactions</title>
<link href="http://www.windley.com/archives/2008/04/tyler_close_using_promises_to_orchestrate_web_interactions.shtml"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Phil Windley blogs about
<a href="http://www2008.org/program/program-DevTrack.html#seven">my WWW 2008
presentation</a> of the <a href="bang/">ref_send library for
Javascript</a>.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#3</id>
<updated>2008-03-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>upgrade: Live fast, die young and leave a good-looking corpse</title>
<link href="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/upgrade/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Any application that keeps state needs a plan for maintaining it as the
application evolves. Successfully managing these upgrades is one of the more
challenging aspects of application development. This document explains several
patterns and techniques for managing upgrade in a Waterken application.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#2</id>
<updated>2008-03-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>W3C Note on browser security UI finishes Last Call</title>
<link href="http://www.w3.org/TR/wsc-usecases/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>This publication completes my duties as editor for the W3C Web Security
Context Working Group. I think the
<a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/wsc-usecases/#problems">Problems with the status
quo</a> section provides a good summary of the challenges facing the group.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#1</id>
<updated>2007-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
<title>web-key: Mashing with permission</title>
<link href="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/web-key/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Mashups, web applications that interact with other web applications, are
receiving increasing developer interest and providing users with valuable new
functionality. When one or more of the interacting applications have access
control requirements, many design challenges arise. Failure to meet these
challenges brings unnecessary risk to the user.  Addressing the challenges
using a poorly suited technique can add significant complexity to both the
application code and the user interface, all while not reducing risk to the
user.  In addition to examining and explaining these failings, this paper
introduces a solution, the web-key, an https URL convention for representing a
transferable permission in a web application.  Using web-keys, access control
challenges can be effectively solved using existing development tools for web
applications deployed to existing web browsers.</p>
</div>
</content>
</entry>

</feed>
