<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="recent.xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
      xml:base="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/">

<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent</id>
<updated>2008-10-16Z</updated>
<title>Waterken News</title>
<subtitle>Capability-based security on the Web</subtitle>
<link href="recent.html"/>
<link rel="self" href="recent.xml"/>
<logo>site/icon.gif</logo>
<icon>site/icon.gif</icon>
<author><name>Tyler Close</name></author>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#7</id>
<updated>2008-10-15Z</updated>
<title>clickjacking: The Confused Deputy rides again!</title>
<link href="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/clickjacking/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The
<a href="http://ha.ckers.org/blog/20080915/clickjacking/">announcement of the
clickjacking research</a> ignited interest in a number of Web exploits, some of
which seem new and others similar to known exploits. Already, there's lots of
<a href="http://blog.whatwg.org/this-week-in-html-5-episode-7">discussion of
possible workarounds</a>, mainly focused on changes to the application's user
interface, or the browser's rendering logic. While the flexibility of the
browser's user interface languages gives clickjacking a polished look, this
flexibility isn't actually what enables these attacks. That blame lies with the
ambient authority model used by most web applications. If applications instead
used an explicit authorization model, they would not be vulnerable to
clickjacking and there would be no need to reduce the flexibility of the
browser's user interface languages. Web applications can be implemented to an
explicit authorization model without any change to Web protocols or
formats.</p>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#6</id>
<updated>2008-09-25Z</updated>
<title>Petname Tool: updated for Firefox 3</title>
<link href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/957"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I've ported the Petname Tool to the new
Places API for bookmarks in Firefox 3.</p>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#5</id>
<updated>2008-07-24Z</updated>
<title>Can the evolution of programming languages inform usable security?</title>
<link href="http://usablesecurity.com/2008/07/24/testing-for-usable-security-what-relationship-if-any-does-it-have-to-product-design/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Richard Conlan blogs about a SOUPS 2008
panel that I participated in.</p>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#4</id>
<updated>2008-04-25Z</updated>
<title>Using promises to orchestrate Web interactions</title>
<link href="http://www.windley.com/archives/2008/04/tyler_close_using_promises_to_orchestrate_web_interactions.shtml"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Phil Windley blogs about
<a href="http://www2008.org/program/program-DevTrack.html#seven">my WWW 2008
presentation</a> of the <a href="bang/">ref_send library for
Javascript</a>.</p>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#3</id>
<updated>2008-03-22Z</updated>
<title>upgrade: Live fast, die young and leave a good-looking corpse</title>
<link href="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/upgrade/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Any application that keeps state needs
a plan for maintaining it as the application evolves. Successfully managing
these upgrades is one of the more challenging aspects of application
development. This document explains several patterns and techniques for
managing upgrade in a Waterken application.</p>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#2</id>
<updated>2008-03-06Z</updated>
<title>W3C Note on browser security UI finishes Last Call</title>
<link href="http://www.w3.org/TR/wsc-usecases/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This publication completes my duties as
editor for the W3C Web Security Context Working Group. I think the <a
href="http://www.w3.org/TR/wsc-usecases/#problems">Problems with the status
quo</a> section provides a good summary of the challenges facing the group.</p>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>http://waterken.sourceforge.net/recent#1</id>
<updated>2007-10-28Z</updated>
<title>web-key: Mashing with Permission</title>
<link href="http://waterken.sourceforge.net/web-key/"/>
<content type="xhtml">
<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Mashups, web applications that interact
with other web applications, are receiving increasing developer interest and
providing users with valuable new functionality. When one or more of the
interacting applications have access control requirements, many design
challenges arise. Failure to meet these challenges brings unnecessary risk to
the user.  Addressing the challenges using a poorly suited technique can add
significant complexity to both the application code and the user interface, all
while not reducing risk to the user.  In addition to examining and explaining
these failings, this paper introduces a solution, the web-key, an https URL
convention for representing a transferable permission in a web application.
Using web-keys, access control challenges can be effectively solved using
existing development tools for web applications deployed to existing web
browsers.</p>
</content>
</entry>

</feed>
